<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>We launch on Friday</title>
    <link>https://rtjom.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on We launch on Friday</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 21:01:51 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rtjom.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Crossing the Rubicon</title>
      <link>https://rtjom.com/blog/2021/02/crossing-the-rubicon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 21:01:51 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rtjom.com/blog/2021/02/crossing-the-rubicon/</guid>
      <description>Every now and then I keep hearing the phrase &amp;ldquo;crossing the Rubicon&amp;rdquo;, yet I have never actually thought about its origins and meaning. In &amp;ldquo;Meditations: a new translation&amp;rdquo; Gregory Hays mentioned that event and explains it. Here is an exerpt from Wikipedia:
 Julius Caesar&amp;rsquo;s crossing the Rubicon river in January 49 BC precipitated the Roman Civil War, which ultimately led to Caesar becoming dictator and the rise of the imperial era of Rome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary February 2021</title>
      <link>https://rtjom.com/blog/2021/02/summary-february-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 08:14:07 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rtjom.com/blog/2021/02/summary-february-2021/</guid>
      <description>I was hoping that the biggest even of February would be puppy school, but Covid took the lead bringing down both myself, and my whole family after me.
 puppy training with border collie krav maga 10 paying clients  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary January 2021</title>
      <link>https://rtjom.com/blog/2021/02/summary-january-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 07:58:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rtjom.com/blog/2021/02/summary-january-2021/</guid>
      <description>The moment I stop taking notes and leave writing this blog post for a week or two, all my memories of the past month events vanish. Partly this is because nothing big happens, and the life is pretty much the same. With a young kid every day is almost a groundhog day. Luckily, I can point out few events that made this month stand out a bit&amp;hellip;
About 5 years ago I moved back to Tallinn from London and decided to start a honey business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Launches on Producthunt</title>
      <link>https://rtjom.com/blog/2021/01/two-launches-on-producthunt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 12:31:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rtjom.com/blog/2021/01/two-launches-on-producthunt/</guid>
      <description>Last week I launched shipit (a tool for product managers to help plan and manage their product) on Product Hunt for the second time. I hesitated whether I should do it or not, but the results were very unexpected.
I spent nearly two weeks preparing the first round, reading about the timing, the importance of famous hunters, your first comment, and the support of community. I failed to find someone to hunt us, so did it myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Algorithms and Manipulation</title>
      <link>https://rtjom.com/blog/2021/01/on-algorithms-and-manipulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 20:24:51 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rtjom.com/blog/2021/01/on-algorithms-and-manipulation/</guid>
      <description>Few years ago there was a mass-shooting in San Bernardino. FBI seized the phone of one of the shooters and asked Apple to decrypt it. Apple refused citing the protection of its users not matter what. Ask any person on the street or among your friends who is right here, and the would most likely side with the FBI. After all, a person who massacred 14 people by definition cannot have the right to privacy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary December 2020</title>
      <link>https://rtjom.com/blog/2020/12/summary-december-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2020 08:11:51 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rtjom.com/blog/2020/12/summary-december-2020/</guid>
      <description>It looks like December has been the most fruitful and event-rich month of the year.
Dog I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to have a dog, and about 4 years when I realized things are going sour with my finances, and the investments I made are going to require most of my money, I had to put the idea of owning a dog away. Since few months ago after I got rid of that project, the thought of owning a dog started to become more real.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary November 2020</title>
      <link>https://rtjom.com/blog/2020/12/summary-november-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2020 08:10:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rtjom.com/blog/2020/12/summary-november-2020/</guid>
      <description>Another monthly update that I wanted to write in the beginning of the month before forgetting everything. Life with two small kids is becoming more and more complicated.
Funny how the opinion on 1 vs 2 kids changes from meh, that&amp;rsquo;s easy, and I have lots of energy and free time, and we can have a third kid in the first month. Then in the second month things start to settle down and you have less energy, but still capable of following all your life activities like sports, hobbies, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary October 2020</title>
      <link>https://rtjom.com/blog/2020/10/summary-october-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 14:43:06 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rtjom.com/blog/2020/10/summary-october-2020/</guid>
      <description>What happens when something drags you for so long that you forget what the normal life looks like? When you have a constant buzz in your ear, or a never-ending pain in the shoulder, you get used to living with that. Likewise I got involved in an extremely bad investment 5 years ago that changed the course of my life considerably.
I got invited by a family friend to participate in a project, and I approved of it to one of my close family members.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary September 2020</title>
      <link>https://rtjom.com/blog/2020/10/summary-september-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 14:31:43 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rtjom.com/blog/2020/10/summary-september-2020/</guid>
      <description>When you miss the deadline for writing a regular blog post and haven&amp;rsquo;t left any notes, it becomes really hard to remember what happend in that month. Nothing special, I guess, since I don&amp;rsquo;t remember much. But here are a few notes&amp;hellip;
My RC car project got stalled for quite a while for various reasons. After disassembling the chassis I started modelling new motor mounts to support a motor for each wheel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary August 2020</title>
      <link>https://rtjom.com/blog/2020/09/summary-august-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 14:56:46 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rtjom.com/blog/2020/09/summary-august-2020/</guid>
      <description>Having your first child changes everything in life. Eventually you adapt to the new lifestyle. New habits develop. You learn to better plan your time if you want some personal space. Then the second child arrives and everything changes again. You go through the same process again. I kind of expected it won&amp;rsquo;t be easy, but didn&amp;rsquo;t know in which way. In every way!
Having a second child was a huge event in August, but there are other things that happened as well: August ended with me doing sports for two months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary July 2020</title>
      <link>https://rtjom.com/blog/2020/08/summary-july-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 22:56:41 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rtjom.com/blog/2020/08/summary-july-2020/</guid>
      <description>July has been another interesting month in my startup life. My co-founder has moved back to his home country leaving me alone in Estonia. Not that it&amp;rsquo;s a big deal and means an end to our company, but it&amp;rsquo;s still a bit of a blow to the social part of the company. Now it became remote-only with all three co-founders spread across Europe.
We haven&amp;rsquo;t had any new customers in July, but I started turning more attention to marketing and sales.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary June 2020</title>
      <link>https://rtjom.com/blog/2020/06/summary-june-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 09:34:09 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rtjom.com/blog/2020/06/summary-june-2020/</guid>
      <description>My sports habits continued in June and I have been going to the climbing gym throughout the whole month. As a result my climbing problem skills went from the simple 1-3 (using French grading system) to starting doing 4-grade problems. Each session is followed up with some fitness excersizes. It helps to train with a buddy as you are constantly pushed to rest less, train more, and climb increasingly more complex routes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary May 2020</title>
      <link>https://rtjom.com/blog/2020/06/summary-may-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 08:54:22 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rtjom.com/blog/2020/06/summary-may-2020/</guid>
      <description>May saw the relaxing of the quarantine rules, and at the beginning of the month restaurants started to open up. We went to one and were the only people there.
While I was in high school I used to ride a dirt bike. These were fun times and in the process I made some good friends and broke a few bones and had several brain concussions. This bike was in my parents&amp;rsquo; garage since then, until I sold it few weeks ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why you shouldn&#39;t become an angel investor</title>
      <link>https://rtjom.com/blog/2020/05/why-you-shouldnt-become-an-angel-investor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 09:40:31 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rtjom.com/blog/2020/05/why-you-shouldnt-become-an-angel-investor/</guid>
      <description>For many people like me, angel investing is akin to being a pirate. You sail the vast seas in search of the Urca de Lima of startups. Every encounter with the navy ship (the WeWork of our time) can cause you your life,get decapitated, or your team turns against you and leave on a deserted island with just a single bottle of rum. But every once in a while some pirate (which could be you) hit that cargo ship with gold bullion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary April 2020</title>
      <link>https://rtjom.com/blog/2020/05/summary-april-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 09:07:15 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rtjom.com/blog/2020/05/summary-april-2020/</guid>
      <description>April was the second month of the pandemic and lockdowns here in Estonia. We were already staying at home since the end of February, so not much has changed. It took a way longer than I hoped for to adapt to the new work-life balance. As a result, I moved to a somewhat flexible working hours, several smaller chunks with longer breaks instead of a one long 9-5 day. When you have two working adults and a toddler, it&amp;rsquo;s next to impossible to do deep work unless you wake up very early in the morning (which I don&amp;rsquo;t).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary March 2020</title>
      <link>https://rtjom.com/blog/2020/03/summary-march-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 16:12:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rtjom.com/blog/2020/03/summary-march-2020/</guid>
      <description>Well, March and likely next few months are going to be all about the virus, self-isolation, and remote work. Both me and my wife have IT-related jobs which are easy to make remote. I&amp;rsquo;ve been working remotely for the past 5 years so it&amp;rsquo;s nothing new. What is different though is that our kiddo is also staying home with us, and it&amp;rsquo;s been nightmare&amp;rsquo;ish, to say the least.
In the past two weeks we&amp;rsquo;ve all been adapting to the new reality: trying to find time and space for some deep work, getting personal time and space outside work, and having enough ideas and games to get the toddler busy and entertained.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Walk Around Pelgulinn</title>
      <link>https://rtjom.com/blog/2020/03/a-walk-around-pelgulinn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 22:34:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rtjom.com/blog/2020/03/a-walk-around-pelgulinn/</guid>
      <description>Tallinn is divided into 8 districts which in turn are sub-divided into smaller parts. While everyone who lives in the city they were born think they know the place, tourists and expacts usually know way more. When I lived in London I loved to explore tiny villages that the city eventually consumed. When you arrive there the place still feels like a village. In a series of blog posts I want to explore my own city&amp;rsquo;s sub districts and map them here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading</title>
      <link>https://rtjom.com/reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 20:02:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rtjom.com/reading/</guid>
      <description>Reading queue  &amp;ldquo;Living My Life&amp;rdquo; by Emma Goldman John Toland&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Letters to Serena&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Days of War, Nights of Love&amp;rdquo; Crimethink for Beginners &amp;ldquo;Momo&amp;rdquo; by Michael Ende &amp;ldquo;Letters to a Young Poet&amp;rdquo; by Rainer Maria Rilke &amp;ldquo;Six easy pieces&amp;rdquo; by Richard Feinman &amp;ldquo;Thing Explainer&amp;rdquo; by Randall Munroe &amp;ldquo;Thinking Physics&amp;rdquo; - by Lewis Carroll Epstein &amp;ldquo;The story of Phylosophy&amp;rdquo; - by Will Durant  Currently reading  &amp;ldquo;Genome: The Autobiography Of A Species In 23 Chapters&amp;rdquo; by Matt Ridley &amp;ldquo;Catch 22&amp;rdquo; by Joseph Heller &amp;ldquo;Divine comedy&amp;rdquo; by Dante Alighieri  Read  &amp;ldquo;Meditations: a new translation&amp;quot;, translated by Gregory Hays &amp;ldquo;Ami: child of the stars&amp;rdquo; by Enrique Barrios &amp;ldquo;The Lessons of History&amp;rdquo; by Will Durant  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary - February 2020</title>
      <link>https://rtjom.com/blog/2020/02/summary-february-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 10:51:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rtjom.com/blog/2020/02/summary-february-2020/</guid>
      <description>Being a cold loving person I recently saw a temperature map of Europe showing that throughout the whole continent it&amp;rsquo;s above zero. To say that I was shocked is understatement.
![temperature map of Europe](/images/temperature-map-europe.gif) In my memory this is the first winter ever without any snow. Not only that, but we&amp;rsquo;ve got flowers blooming in February! Whenever I take my child to the kindergarten we count how many different types of flowers we spot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://rtjom.com/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 16:43:35 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rtjom.com/projects/</guid>
      <description>Shipit shipit is a startup that I co-founded with Till. Its goal is to help product managers plan their roadmaps and manage the whole product lifecycle, from receiving customer feedback to prioritization and presentation.
Elm Bits (on pause) A newsletter about everything related to Elm programming language. After finding out about this tech I got really excited about functional programming and wanted to learn more about the language. Every week I shared the news, articles, and other bits with subscribers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://rtjom.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 15:44:01 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rtjom.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello, my name is Artjom (which is pronounced as &amp;ldquo;artiom&amp;rdquo;).
I am technical co-founder of getshipit.com which is a tool to help product managers plan their roadmap and manage product lifecycle. At the moment of this writing (Feb 2020) we&amp;rsquo;re still a tiny company where I&amp;rsquo;m involved in everything: from writing code to customer support, advertising, planning.
Elm Bits is my weekly email with everything about the Elm programming language. I started that as a way to learn more about the language and functional programming in general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Startup Perks and Benefits</title>
      <link>https://rtjom.com/blog/2018/10/startup-perks-and-benefits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 10:39:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rtjom.com/blog/2018/10/startup-perks-and-benefits/</guid>
      <description>I work for a startup called Juggle Jobs. We’re the goto place to people to find flexible work. We help early parents to find a challenging part-time work so they could spend the early months with their newborns and not feel a massive hole in their family budget. We help people find a job in multiple companies at the same time, something we call a portfolio career, where you spend several days a months at a company, for example, as their CFO.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Wtforms With Selectfield and Fieldlist</title>
      <link>https://rtjom.com/blog/2016/10/using-wtforms-with-selectfield-and-fieldlist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 15:30:45 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rtjom.com/blog/2016/10/using-wtforms-with-selectfield-and-fieldlist/</guid>
      <description>WTForms is an amazing library that helps with the forms creation, validation, rendering. Instead of validating each field separately in your code, all you need to do is run form.validate().
SelectField Using WTForms is straightforward for most common fields, however when the use-case gets a bit complicated, the documentation is not of much help. Recently I had to create a project with a lot of dynamic fields and validation where I used SelectField, SelectMultipleField, and FieldList among others.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>