<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>We launch on Friday</title>
    <link>https://rtjom.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on We launch on Friday</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 16:12:23 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rtjom.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary March 2020</title>
      <link>https://rtjom.com/blog/2020/03/summary-march-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 16:12:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rtjom.com/blog/2020/03/summary-march-2020/</guid>
      <description>Well, March and likely next few months are going to be all about the virus, self-isolation, and remote work. Both me and my wife have IT-related jobs which are easy to make remote. I&amp;rsquo;ve been working remotely for the past 5 years so it&amp;rsquo;s nothing new. What is different though is that our kiddo is also staying home with us, and it&amp;rsquo;s been nightmare&amp;rsquo;ish, to say the least.
In the past two weeks we&amp;rsquo;ve all been adapting to the new reality: trying to find time and space for some deep work, getting personal time and space outside work, and having enough ideas and games to get the toddler busy and entertained.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Walk Around Pelgulinn</title>
      <link>https://rtjom.com/blog/2020/03/a-walk-around-pelgulinn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 22:34:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rtjom.com/blog/2020/03/a-walk-around-pelgulinn/</guid>
      <description>Tallinn is divided into 8 districts which in turn are sub-divided into smaller parts. While everyone who lives in the city they were born think they know the place, tourists and expacts usually know way more. When I lived in London I loved to explore tiny villages that the city eventually consumed. When you arrive there the place still feels like a village. In a series of blog posts I want to explore my own city&amp;rsquo;s sub districts and map them here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary - February 2020</title>
      <link>https://rtjom.com/blog/2020/02/summary-february-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 10:51:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rtjom.com/blog/2020/02/summary-february-2020/</guid>
      <description>Being a cold loving person I recently saw a temperature map of Europe showing that throughout the whole continent it&amp;rsquo;s above zero. To say that I was shocked is understatement.

In my memory this is the first winter ever without any snow. Not only that, but we&amp;rsquo;ve got flowers blooming in February! Whenever I take my child to the kindergarten we count how many different types of flowers we spot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://rtjom.com/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 16:43:35 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rtjom.com/projects/</guid>
      <description>Shipit shipit is a startup that I co-founded with Till. Its goal is to help product managers plan their roadmaps and manage the whole product lifecycle, from receiving customer feedback to prioritization and presentation.
Elm Bits A newsletter about everything related to Elm programming language. After finding out about this tech I got really excited about functional programming and wanted to learn more about the language. Every week I shared the news, articles, and other bits with subscribers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://rtjom.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 15:44:01 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rtjom.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello, my name is Artjom (which is pronounced as &amp;ldquo;artiom&amp;rdquo;).
I am technical co-founder of getshipit.com which is a tool to help product managers plan their roadmap and manage product lifecycle. At the moment of this writing (Feb 2020) we&amp;rsquo;re still a tiny company where I&amp;rsquo;m involved in everything: from writing code to customer support, advertising, planning.
Elm Bits is my weekly email with everything about the Elm programming language. I started that as a way to learn more about the language and functional programming in general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Startup Perks and Benefits</title>
      <link>https://rtjom.com/blog/2018/10/startup-perks-and-benefits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 10:39:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rtjom.com/blog/2018/10/startup-perks-and-benefits/</guid>
      <description>I work for a startup called Juggle Jobs. We’re the goto place to people to find flexible work. We help early parents to find a challenging part-time work so they could spend the early months with their newborns and not feel a massive hole in their family budget. We help people find a job in multiple companies at the same time, something we call a portfolio career, where you spend several days a months at a company, for example, as their CFO.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Wtforms With Selectfield and Fieldlist</title>
      <link>https://rtjom.com/blog/2016/10/using-wtforms-with-selectfield-and-fieldlist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 15:30:45 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rtjom.com/blog/2016/10/using-wtforms-with-selectfield-and-fieldlist/</guid>
      <description>WTForms is an amazing library that helps with the forms creation, validation, rendering. Instead of validating each field separately in your code, all you need to do is run form.validate().
SelectField Using WTForms is straightforward for most common fields, however when the use-case gets a bit complicated, the documentation is not of much help. Recently I had to create a project with a lot of dynamic fields and validation where I used SelectField, SelectMultipleField, and FieldList among others.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>